{
"0": {"front": "School day was ___ days long in 1900", 
"back": "100 days long, 40% shorter than today"},
"1": {"front": "% of US studnets who go to college?", 
"back": "68%. And only 60% of these manage to get their degree within 6 years."},
"2": {"front": "% of teachers that feel under great stress? % who are likely to leave the profession in the next 5 years?", 
"back": "50% feel under great stress. 1/3 likley to leave."},
"3": {"front": "% of moms without a highschool degree who have children born outside of marriage?", 
"back": "62%"},
"4": {"front": "% of public school parents who gave public schools a C grade or lower? % three decades ago?", 
"back": "80% today. 56% three decades ago."},
"5": {"front": "Number of: K-12 students? Schools? Teachers?", 
"back": "52 million students. 100,000 schools. 3 million teachers"},
"6": {"front": "% of public school parents who oppose Common Core?", 
"back": "62% in opposition"},
"7": {"front": "% of public school parents who think the local school board should have the most say? % who say the federal government?", 
"back": "60% local school board. 12% federal government"},
"8": {"front": "", 
"back": "transparently clear; easily understandable"},
"9": {"front": "afflict", 
"back": "cause physical pain or suffering in"},
"10": {"front": "roil", 
"back": "be agitated"},
"11": {"front": "warrant", 
"back": "show to be reasonable or provide adequate ground for"},
"12": {"front": "philology", 
"back": "the humanistic study of language and literature"},
"13": {"front": "pedantic", 
"back": "marked by a narrow focus on or display of learning"},
"14": {"front": "squeamish", 
"back": "excessively fastidious and easily disgusted"},
"15": {"front": "execrable", 
"back": "unequivocally detestable"},
"16": {"front": "deference", 
"back": "a courteous expression of esteem or regard"},
"17": {"front": "reverie", 
"back": "an abstracted state of absorption"},
"18": {"front": "enduring", 
"back": "unceasing"},
"19": {"front": "prude", 
"back": "a person excessively concerned about propriety and decorum"},
"20": {"front": "passe", 
"back": "out of fashion"},
"21": {"front": "apparent", 
"back": "clearly revealed to the mind or the senses or judgment"},
"22": {"front": "gainsay", 
"back": "take exception to"},
"23": {"front": "temper", 
"back": "a characteristic state of feeling"},
"24": {"front": "derelict", 
"back": "in deplorable condition"},
"25": {"front": "pendulous", 
"back": "hanging loosely or bending downward"},
"26": {"front": "emetic", 
"back": "a medicine that induces nausea and vomiting"},
"27": {"front": "pilfer", 
"back": "make off with belongings of others"},
"28": {"front": "institute", 
"back": "set up or lay the groundwork for"},
"29": {"front": "sinecure", 
"back": "a job that involves minimal duties"},
"30": {"front": "grandiloquent", 
"back": "lofty in style"},
"31": {"front": "placate", 
"back": "cause to be more favorably inclined"},
"32": {"front": "humble", 
"back": "marked by meekness or modesty; not arrogant or prideful"},
"33": {"front": "bemuse", 
"back": "cause to be confused emotionally"},
"34": {"front": "connotation", 
"back": "an idea that is implied or suggested"},
"35": {"front": "urbane", 
"back": "showing a high degree of refinement"},
"36": {"front": "tribunal", 
"back": "an assembly to conduct judicial business"},
"37": {"front": "cede", 
"back": "relinquish possession or control over"},
"38": {"front": "prowess", 
"back": "a superior skill learned by study and practice "},
"39": {"front": "mundane", 
"back": "found in the ordinary course of events"},
"40": {"front": "wreak", 
"back": "cause to happen or to occur as a consequence"},
"41": {"front": "disquisition", 
"back": "an elaborate analytical or explanatory essay or discussion"},
"42": {"front": "cupidity", 
"back": "extreme greed for material wealth"},
"43": {"front": "commission", 
"back": "a special group delegated to consider some matter"},
"44": {"front": "fervent", 
"back": "characterized by intense emotion"},
"45": {"front": "stump", 
"back": "cause to be perplexed or confounded"},
"46": {"front": "pacifist", 
"back": "opposed to war"},
"47": {"front": "policy", 
"back": "a plan of action adopted by an individual or social group"},
"48": {"front": "slay", 
"back": "kill intentionally and with premeditation"},
"49": {"front": "libretto", 
"back": "the words of an opera or musical play"},
"50": {"front": "onset", 
"back": "the beginning or early stages"},
"51": {"front": "stratum", 
"back": "people having the same social or economic status"},
"52": {"front": "straight", 
"back": "successive, without a break"},
"53": {"front": "assiduous", 
"back": "marked by care and persistent effort"},
"54": {"front": "wraith", 
"back": "a mental representation of some haunting experience"},
"55": {"front": "adage", 
"back": "a condensed but memorable saying embodying an important fact"},
"56": {"front": "dogged", 
"back": "stubbornly unyielding"},
"57": {"front": "exploit", 
"back": "draw from; make good use of"},
"58": {"front": "loquacious", 
"back": "full of trivial conversation"},
"59": {"front": "novel", 
"back": "an extended fictional work in prose"},
"60": {"front": "edifice", 
"back": "a structure that has a roof and walls"},
"61": {"front": "malaise", 
"back": "a general feeling of discomfort, uneasiness, or depression"},
"62": {"front": "liberal", 
"back": "having political views favoring reform and progress"},
"63": {"front": "exorbitant", 
"back": "greatly exceeding bounds of reason or moderation"},
"64": {"front": "confluence", 
"back": "a flowing together"},
"65": {"front": "imposture", 
"back": "pretending to be another person"},
"66": {"front": "odium", 
"back": "state of disgrace resulting from detestable behavior"},
"67": {"front": "repast", 
"back": "the food served and eaten at one time"},
"68": {"front": "obdurate", 
"back": "stubbornly persistent in wrongdoing"},
"69": {"front": "beatific", 
"back": "resembling or befitting an angel or saint"},
"70": {"front": "implacable", 
"back": "incapable of being appeased or pacified"},
"71": {"front": "frieze", 
"back": "an ornament consisting of a horizontal sculptured band"},
"72": {"front": "gibe", 
"back": "laugh at with contempt and derision"},
"73": {"front": "roseate", 
"back": "of something having a dusty purplish pink color"},
"74": {"front": "pervade", 
"back": "spread or diffuse through"},
"75": {"front": "dapper", 
"back": "marked by up-to-dateness in dress and manners"},
"76": {"front": "kindle", 
"back": "catch fire"},
"77": {"front": "callous", 
"back": "emotionally hardened"},
"78": {"front": "manifestation", 
"back": "a clear appearance"},
"79": {"front": "ratify", 
"back": "approve and express assent, responsibility, or obligation"},
"80": {"front": "accede", 
"back": "yield to another's wish or opinion"},
"81": {"front": "effulgence", 
"back": "the quality of being bright and sending out rays of light"},
"82": {"front": "abstemious", 
"back": "marked by temperance in indulgence"},
"83": {"front": "erode", 
"back": "become ground down or deteriorate"},
"84": {"front": "propitious", 
"back": "presenting favorable circumstances"},
"85": {"front": "cardinal", 
"back": "one of a group of prominent bishops in the Sacred College"},
"86": {"front": "insist", 
"back": "be emphatic or resolute and refuse to budge"},
"87": {"front": "sleight", 
"back": "adroitness in using the hands"},
"88": {"front": "frustrate", 
"back": "hinder or prevent, as an effort, plan, or desire"},
"89": {"front": "errant", 
"back": "straying from the right course or from accepted standards"},
"90": {"front": "traduce", 
"back": "speak unfavorably about"},
"91": {"front": "purvey", 
"back": "supply with provisions"},
"92": {"front": "discriminating", 
"back": "showing or indicating careful judgment and discernment"},
"93": {"front": "lineament", 
"back": "the characteristic parts of a person's face"},
"94": {"front": "malcontent", 
"back": "a person who is unsatisfied or disgusted"},
"95": {"front": "sextant", 
"back": "an instrument for measuring angular distance"},
"96": {"front": "expiate", 
"back": "make amends for"},
"97": {"front": "muster", 
"back": "gather or bring together"},
"98": {"front": "projection", 
"back": "a prediction made by extrapolating from past observations"},
"99": {"front": "estrange", 
"back": "arouse hostility or indifference in"},
"100": {"front": "effluvium", 
"back": "a foul-smelling outflow or vapor"},
"101": {"front": "welt", 
"back": "a raised mark on the skin "},
"102": {"front": "fresco", 
"back": "a mural done with watercolors on wet plaster"},
"103": {"front": "audacious", 
"back": "disposed to venture or take risks"},
"104": {"front": "toil", 
"back": "work hard"},
"105": {"front": "libertine", 
"back": "a dissolute person"},
"106": {"front": "ranging", 
"back": "wandering freely"},
"107": {"front": "contempt", 
"back": "lack of respect accompanied by a feeling of intense dislike"},
"108": {"front": "aggrieve", 
"back": "infringe on the rights of"},
"109": {"front": "undertaking", 
"back": "any piece of work that is attempted"},
"110": {"front": "pastoral", 
"back": "idyllically rustic"},
"111": {"front": "disconsolate", 
"back": "sad beyond comforting; incapable of being consoled"},
"112": {"front": "mortify", 
"back": "cause to feel shame"},
"113": {"front": "fulminate", 
"back": "criticize severely"},
"114": {"front": "automate", 
"back": "operate or make run by machines rather than human action"},
"115": {"front": "imperturbable", 
"back": "marked by extreme calm and composure"},
"116": {"front": "apropos", 
"back": "of an appropriate or pertinent nature"},
"117": {"front": "slew", 
"back": "a large number or amount or extent"},
"118": {"front": "prognosticate", 
"back": "make a prediction about; tell in advance"},
"119": {"front": "refractory", 
"back": "stubbornly resistant to authority or control"},
"120": {"front": "discretionary", 
"back": "not earmarked; available for use as needed"},
"121": {"front": "careen", 
"back": "pitching dangerously to one side"},
"122": {"front": "sate", 
"back": "fill to contentment"},
"123": {"front": "approach", 
"back": "move towards"}
}